This episode of Primal Space is supported by Skillshare.
过去几年 我们亲眼目睹了太空叉从德州一块烂泥地起家
Over the last couple of years, we've seen SpaceX go from a dirt field in Texas
到如今发射了当前最先进火箭的原型机
to launching prototypes of the most advanced rocket ever made.
博卡奇卡小镇上如火如荼的研发工作是如此令人着迷
The exciting developments down in Boca Chica have been mesmerizing to watch
大家也很清楚 太空叉要在Starship项目上投入大量资源
and it's clear that SpaceX are now all in on making Starship a success.
未来 他们打算运营一批Starship舰队
In the future, they plan to have a fleet of Starships,
从世界各地起飞 飞往诸如月球、火星之类的目的地 甚至是地球上的其他地方
launching all around the world with destinations such as the Moon, Mars and even other places here on Earth.
他们想让Starship成为像民航客机一样
They want to operate Starship just like an airliner,
每艘飞船运几百名乘客 每天飞行几班
with each vehicle carrying hundreds of passengers and doing multiple flights per day.
但很多人认为这种想法虽然很令人兴奋 但还是太理想了
But many think this exciting future is just too good to be true.
在发射的时候 全尺寸的Starship声音将会非常巨大
Upon launch, a fully assembled Starship will be incredibly loud.
在超重型助推器上的28台猛禽发动机工作时
With around 28 raptor engines on the Super Heavy booster,
即使远在8公里外 声音强度仍可能高达112分贝
the sound level - even from 8 kilometres away - would be around 112 decibels.
这就好比有个站在你身边用电锯一样
This is like someone using a chainsaw while standing right next to you.
这种级别的噪声不但对附近的民居产生严重影响
Not only would this sound level be extremely disruptive to nearby residents,
甚至可能非常危险
it could also be extremely dangerous.
你离Starship越近
The closer to Starship you get,
声波的能量就越高 甚至可能击碎玻璃 摧毁建筑
the sound waves become powerful enough to smash windows and damage buildings.
如果太空叉希望Starship达到自己预想的发射频率
If Starship launches are to be as frequent as SpaceX hope,
那他们就要让发射台和着陆场尽可能离居民区远
they will need to move the launch and landing pads far away from civilization.
早期Starship的CG中可以看到离岸几英里的一个发射平台
Early renders of Starship show a sleek looking launch platform several miles off shore.
他们希望Starship能够在这个平台上完成起降 完全不用回到陆地上
The idea is that Starships would launch and land
from these platforms without ever having to go back to dry land.
但放眼的全球人类航天史 这其实并不是新鲜事
But even in the world of spaceflight, this isn't a new idea.
早在九十年代建立的海上发射公司
The company 'Sea Launch' which started back in the 90's,
主要业务就是在石油钻井改装后的海上浮动发射平台发射天顶号火箭
specialized in launching the Zenit rocket from a floating sea platform which used to be a former oil rig.
可能看起来阵势不大 但发射的火箭可一点都不小
Although it may seem like quite a small operation, this was no small rocket.
天顶号火箭和猎鹰九号大小差不多 入轨运力也相近
The Zenit was almost the same size as the Falcon 9 and could carry a similar amount of mass into orbit.
在那个年代 海射公司搞得非常成功
In its day, Sea Launch was pretty successful.
但高昂的运营成本和少的可怜的发射记录最终还是让他们破产了
But high running costs and a lack of flights eventually caused them to go bankrupt.
但海射公司成功证明了海上发射的种种好处
However, Sea Launch demonstrated that there are a lot of benefits to launching from the sea.
当从卡纳维拉尔角这种传统发射场发射的时候
When launching from typical launch sites like Cape Canaveral,
火箭不可以从人口稠密区域上空飞行 所以它们通常是面向海面发射
rockets aren't allowed to fly over populated areas, so they usually head out over the sea.
这会极大限制火箭能到达的轨道
This drastically limits the range of orbits it can achieve.
而对于地球静止轨道 火箭需要在赤道正上空飞行
For geostationary orbits, rockets need to fly perfectly above the equator
与地球同步自转
and travel with the rotation of Earth.
这意味着火箭要消耗额外燃料飞到赤道上空
This means that the rocket spends much more of its fuel just getting down to the equator.
而如果在海上发射平台发射 那就能抵达任何轨道
When launching from a sea platform, any orbit can be achieved.
这虽然不是太空叉首先考虑的问题
This isn't the main consideration for SpaceX
但对于他们方兴未艾的Starlink星座项目来说
but with their constantly growing Starlink constellation,
一个海上发射平台能够帮助他们到达更广范围的轨道
an offshore launch platform would help them to reach a much wider range of orbits
让他们的卫星能覆盖全球更多范围
and cover the globe with their satellites.
去年 我们看到太空叉拉满了公开招募
Last year, we saw various job postings from SpaceX
广纳各种海上发射平台的工程师与技术员
looking to hire engineers and technicians for offshore launch platforms.
因为目前Starship项目进展太快了
After all, with the incredible pace of Starship's development,
未来海上发射平台方面的人才需求可能会超乎想象
an offshore launch platform could be needed much sooner than expected.
博卡奇卡小镇几英里外就是布朗斯维尔港
Just several miles away from their Boca Chica site is the Port of Brownsville,
很多在墨西哥湾挖油的钻井平台会在那里停留
home to many oil rigs which operate out in the Gulf of Mexico.
如果太空叉将来要搞海上发射平台 那很可能会从这里起步
If SpaceX were working on a future launch platform, it would most likely be happening here.
事实也的确如此 今年年初 一个钻井平台吸引了大家的注意
Sure enough, at the start of this year, one specific oil rig caught everyone's attention.
在布朗斯维尔港众多海上钻井平台中
Sitting amongst the tanker ships in the Port of Brownsville
有一个叫Deimos的海上钻井平台 名字源于火星的一个卫星
was an oil rig sporting the name Deimos, a Moon of Mars.
进一步调查后 这个钻井平台曾隶属于一家叫Valaris的公司
After further investigation, this oil rig used to be owned by a company called Valaris,
该公司于2020年倒闭
which went bankrupt in 2020.
宣告破产后 他们把该平台和另一个
After declaring bankruptcy, they sold this oil rig along with another identical rig
一起卖给了个名叫Lonestar的采矿公司
to a company called Lonestar Mineral Development.
另一个钻井平台也以火星的一个卫星命名 停在得克萨斯州的另一个港口
The other oil rig was also named after a Martian Moon and resided in a port elsewhere in Texas.
Lonestar以单价350万美元买下了Deimos和Phobos两个钻井平台
Lonestar managed to purchase Deimos and Phobos for just $3.5 million each,
相比于自身造价5.15亿美元 已经相当白菜价了
a great price considering these rigs cost $515 million to build.
但这笔交易背后是哪家公司推动的？
But who was the mysterious company behind this transaction?
你猜怎么着？Lonestar矿业公司就是太空叉的子公司
Well as it turns out, Lonestar Mineral Development is a subsidiary of SpaceX.
这基本证实了太空叉打算搞海上发射平台的想法
This confirms that SpaceX are going ahead with their offshore launch platform idea.
但太空叉要怎么把这些海上钻井平台变成Starship的发射着陆场呢？
But how will SpaceX convert these oil rigs to be able to launch and land Starships?
更了更好理解这个问题 我们先来看看太空叉到底都买了啥
To get a better idea, let's take a closer look at the rigs SpaceX have just purchased.
它们是半潜船 可以行进到海中某处并可以抛锚固定位置
These rigs are semi-submersible and can be moved out to sea and anchored in place.
它在水面下还有很大的像船身一样的部分
With large ship-like hulls placed well below the surface,
比太空叉目前的无人船更不容易受到海浪影响
these rigs are much more stable and less affected by waves than SpaceX's current droneships.
每个平台大小是73×78米 8个推进器 每个3500马力
Each rig is 73 by 78 meters wide and has 8 thrusters, each producing around 3,500 horsepower.
因为这些平台会在离岸很远的地方运行 所以都是自带动力的
Since these rigs operate many miles out at sea, they rely on their own power,
本例中是七台巨型柴油发动机
which in this case is provided by 7 enormous diesel engines.
但既然让马一龙接盘了
But since Elon Musk is at the helm of this project,
那他很可能会把它们拆掉
it seems likely that these will be taken out
换成更清洁的可再生能源 比如风能或太阳能
and replaced with a more renewable form of energy, like wind or solar.
在太空叉为Starship改装钻井平台之前
Before SpaceX can start customizing these rigs for Starship,
他们要先拆掉很多之前用于钻探的已有结构
they will need to take down a lot of the existing structures
that were used to support the drilling equipment.
当石油钻井平台的生命周期结束 拆除钻井平台是一件烧钱但非常普遍的事情
Dismantling an oil rig is a costly but very common thing to do,
once it reaches the end of its life cycle.
根据太空叉之前的CG 发射平台顶端应该很简单
Judging by SpaceX's previous renders, the launch platform will be fairly simple on top.
他们需要为着陆区留足空间
They need a large space for the landing area,
要有燃料箱储存燃料 还要有起重机来组装Starship
a tank farm to store propellants and a large crane to lift and stack Starship.
中间的巨塔被称为Derrick 用来支撑所有的重型钻井设备
The large tower in the middle, known as a Derrick,  was used to support all of the heavy drilling equipment.
乍一看 这个塔楼似乎可以作为巨型起重机的地基
At first it may seem like this tower could be used as the foundations for the massive lifting crane.
月池(moon pool)，海上钻井平台钻探设备通往海底的洞
但这个塔下面是月池 是钻井平台上的一个大洞
But underneath this tower is the 'moon pool' which is essentially a giant hole in the platform.
在发射的时候 Starship会产生非常巨大的能量
During launch, the energy produced by Starship's engines will be extremely powerful.
所以太空叉希望把这些能量转移到海上
So SpaceX will want to direct as much of that energy into the sea,
让大海吸收这部分能量 从而保护发射平台
where it will be absorbed instead of damaging the launch platform.
太空叉很可能会利用这个月池
It seems likely that SpaceX will use this moon pool to their advantage
在上面建造发射台 让发动机直接对着海面
and build the launch mount on top, allowing the engines to sit above the water.
太空叉还要建造一整套燃料储存场
SpaceX will also need to build an entire tank farm
储存Starship用于飞行的大量燃料
to contain the enormous amounts of propellants used for flight.
别看博卡奇卡小镇的燃料储存场很大
While the current tank farm in Boca Chica is large,
但也只能用来喂饱Starship原型机
it's only designed to service Starship prototypes,
肯定比全尺寸Starship小得多
which require much less fuel than a fully stacked Starship.
在钻井平台上大概能放下四个这样的燃料储存场
On the oil rig, there is enough space for around 4 of these tank farms.
但为了保护它们 并为着陆场留出空间
But in order to shield the tank farm and free up space for a landing pad,
它们很可能会被放在下层甲板
it will likely be placed below the deck.
接下来问题就是太空叉如何把燃料送到海上发射平台了
Then there is the question of how SpaceX would actually get the propellants to the launch platform.
Starship的主要燃料是液氧和甲烷
The main propellants for Starship are liquid oxygen and liquid methane.
目前这些燃料是由卡车运往博卡奇卡的
Right now, these propellants are currently transported to Boca Chica by truck,
送到后输送到燃料储存场内
where they are unloaded into the tank farm.
为了给海上发射平台加油 他们要定期叫油轮来加油
In order to keep the launch platform filled up, they will rely on regular deliveries from tanker ships.
目前 太空叉正在博卡奇卡搞一个新的工厂
Right now, SpaceX is working on a brand new facility in Boca Chica
让他们能自己生产燃料
which will allow them to start producing their own propellants.
为了产生足够多的燃料
In order to produce a large amount of propellant,
这些工厂规模要非常大 并且需要大量能源
these facilities need to be extremely large and require a huge amount of energy.
太空叉短期内计划在发射平台自行生产液氧
SpaceX's short term plan is to produce their own liquid oxygen from the launch platform
然后让油轮来运输甲烷
while the liquid methane would be delivered by a tanker ship.
而到了未来 太空叉希望使用Sabatier反应来自行生产燃料
In the future though, SpaceX wants to use the Sabatier process to produce their own propellants.
该反应可以让氢和二氧化碳变成氧气和甲烷
This process involves turning hydrogen and carbon dioxide into oxygen and methane,
未来可以让太空叉在火星上自行生产燃料
something SpaceX will need to do to produce propellants on Mars.
走到这一步对于太空叉来说是个不小的挑战
Getting to this point will be very challenging for SpaceX,
但会对他们前往火星的准备提供很多帮助
but the lessons they learn along the way will help them prepare for their first trips to Mars.
如果他们成功做到了
If they are successful in achieving this,
那就能节约很多把燃料运往发射平台所涉及的时间和经济成本
they will cut out the massive costs and time delays
involved in shipping the propellants out to the launch platform.
这又带来另一个问题
This raises yet another problem though.
这些钻井平台服役多年后 表面会留有很多油脂
These rigs will be saturated with oil and grease after many years of service in the oil industry.
再加上火箭尾焰和高压液氧 炸起来一定比SN8 9 10 11还好看
Combining this with rocket flames and high pressure liquid oxygen is a fire hazard on another level.
因此太空叉需要对钻井平台做一个彻底的清洗
So SpaceX will need to do a lot of cleaning on the oil rig
很可能要换掉几乎所有非结构体本身的部件
and will likely need to replace almost everything that isn't part of the structure.
未来几个月 我们可能看到这些钻井平台改装工作陆续开展
In the coming months, we should start to see progress being made on these oil rigs.
一点点扒光 只剩下最基础的结构
Little by little, they will be stripped down until all that's left is the basic structure.
然后太空叉一点点把他们的家伙事搬上来
Then we will really see what SpaceX has in store.
不管怎样 看到太空叉又接下这么一个牛逼的大活还是很有意思的
Either way, it's incredible to see SpaceX yet again take on these incredible challenges
to bring us a future that is equally exciting.
太空叉想要达成此目标
In order for SpaceX to achieve this,
需要很多精通改装钻井平台方面的工程师和技术人员
they will need to hire the best technicians and engineers with expertise in converting oil rigs.
而太空叉做的每一件事
With everything that SpaceX does,
也都是要找各行各业的技能精英
they look for the smartest and most ambitious workers with the right skills for the job.
那么有没有一款……
Skillshare is an online learning community with thousands of classes designed to feed the creativity and curiosity of people like you.
With some of the best teachers at your fingertips, you can learn about anything from photography to music production - all the way to business and entrepreneurship.
In the last few Primal Space videos, you might have noticed the animations have improved.
If animation is also something you'd like to learn or get better at, check out this class called 'Animating With Ease in After Effects' by Jake Barlett.
Whether you're an experienced animator or a complete beginner, this class has something for you.
It takes you through the basic foundations of animating whilst also going into more advanced lessons on how to stylize your animations.
With thousands of classes available on Skillshare, pick the one that's right for you and start learning!
Skillshare has no ads and there are always new premium classes being launched.
The first 1000 people to sign up using the link below will be able to try out Skillshare for free!
非常感谢您的观看 我们下期视频见
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video.